<helpDefinition>
  <title>EC-ESX - Help</title>
  <componentContainer>
	<LINK REL="StyleSheet" HREF="../../plugins/EC-ESX/pluginhelp.css" TYPE="text/css" MEDIA="screen"/>
	<div class="help" >
    
    <h1 class="help">EC-ESX</h1>

    <h2 class="help">Overview</h2>
		<p class="help">
        The EC-ESX plugin allows users to manipulate virtual machines on ESX servers. The plugin provides the following actions to perform on virtual machines: cleanup, clone, create, relocate,  revert, and snapshot. The plugin uses <a href="http://communities.vmware.com/community/developer/forums/vsphere_sdk_perl">vSphere SDK for Perl</a> to accomplish these tasks, which means that you must install the SDK.
		</p>
	
    <h2 class="help">Configuration</h2>
		<p class="help">
		The plugin allows users to store connection configurations in the plugin project.
		</p>
		
		<p class="help">
		To manage your ESX configuration, go to Administration > Plugins and click the EC-ESX <b>Configure</b> link.
		</p>
	
		<p class="help">
		Configurations have the following properties:
		<ul>
			<li>Configuration name - The name of the configuration.</li>
			<li>ESX URL - The URL for the ESX server.</li>
			<li>Credential - Username and password for the ESX server.</li>
		</ul>
		</p>
        
        <p class="help">
		This plugin requires vSphere SDK for Perl. The SDK provides an easy-to-use Perl scripting interface to the vSphere API. You can download the SDK from the <a href="http://communities.vmware.com/community/developer/forums/vsphere_sdk_perl">vSphere SDK for Perl home page</a>. You must have an account to download the SDK. If you do not have an account, you can create one for free.
		</p>
		
	<h2 class="help">Using the Plugin</h2>
		<p class="help">
		When creating a procedure, do the following:
		<ol>
			<li>Click <b>Add Step</b> on the <b>Steps</b> panel.</li>
			<li>Select the Subprocedure category.</li>
			<li>In the Project field, select <b>EC-ESX</b>.</li>
			<li>In the Procedure field, select the procedure you wish to execute: Cleanup, Clone, Create, Relocate, Revert, or Snapshot.</li>
			<li>Click <b>OK</b>.</li>
		</ol>
		</p>
		
		<p class="help">
		The subprocedure you select determines which fields are available.
		</p>		

        	<p class="help">
		The following fields are available for Cleanup:
		<ul>
			<li>connection_config - The name of the configuration that holds connection information for the ESX server (created on the Configure page).</li>
			<li>esx_vmname - Name of the virtual machine to cleanup.</li>
            		<li>esx_save_vm - If unselected, the virtual machine will be destroyed.</li>
            		<li>sdk_installation_path - Absolute path to the SDK installation lib. Default value is 'C:\Program Files\VMware\VMware vSphere CLI\Perl\lib'.</li>
		</ul>
		</p>
		
		<p class="help">
		The following fields are available for Clone:
		<ul>
			<li>connection_config - The name of the configuration that holds connection information for the ESX server (created on the Configure page).</li>
			<li>esx_vmname - Name of the virtual machine whose clone is to be created.</li>
			<li>esx_datastore - Name of the datastore. Default value is the datastore with the most free space.</li>
			<li>esx_vmname_destination - Name of the clone virtual machine that will be created.</li>
			<li>esx_vmhost_destination - Target host for the new virtual machine.</li>
            		<li>sdk_installation_path - Absolute path to the SDK installation lib. Default value is 'C:\Program Files\VMware\VMware vSphere CLI\Perl\lib'.</li>
		</ul>
		</p>
		
		<p class="help">
		The following fields are available for Create:
		<ul>
			<li>connection_config - The name of the configuration that holds connection information for the ESX server (created on the Configure page).</li>
			<li>esx_vmname - Name of the virtual machine to be created.</li>
			<li>esx_datastore - Name of the datastore. Default value is any accessible datastore with free space greater than the disk size specified.</li>
			<li>esx_number_of_vms - Number of virtual machines to create. Default value is 1.</li>
			<li>esx_vmhost - Name of the host.</li>
			<li>esx_datacenter - Name of the datacenter.</li>
			<li>esx_guestid - Guest operating system identifier. Default value is 'winXPProGuest'.</li>
			<li>esx_disksize - Capacity of the virtual disk (in KB). Default value is 4096.</li>
			<li>esx_memory - Size of virtual machine's memory (in MB). Default value is 256.</li>
			<li>esx_num_cpus - Number of virtual processors in a virtual machine. Default value is 1.</li>
            		<li>esx_nic_network - Network name. Default value is any accessible network.</li>
            		<li>esx_nic_poweron - Flag to specify whether or not to connect the device when the virtual machine starts. Default value is 1.</li>
            		<li>sdk_installation_path - Absolute path to the SDK installation lib. Default value is 'C:\Program Files\VMware\VMware vSphere CLI\Perl\lib'.</li>
		</ul>
		</p>
				
		<p class="help">
		The following fields are available for Relocate:
		<ul>
			<li>connection_config - The name of the configuration that holds connection information for the ESX server (created on the Configure page).</li>
			<li>esx_vmname - Name of the virtual machine to be relocated.</li>
			<li>esx_datastore - Name of the datastore. Default value is the datastore with the most free space.</li>
			<li>esx_vmhost_destination - Target host for the virtual machine.</li>
            		<li>sdk_installation_path - Absolute path to the SDK installation lib. Default value is 'C:\Program Files\VMware\VMware vSphere CLI\Perl\lib'.</li>
		</ul>
		</p>      

        
        	<p class="help">
		The following fields are available for Revert:
		<ul>
			<li>connection_config - The name of the configuration that holds connection information for the ESX server (created on the Configure page).</li>
			<li>esx_vmname - Name of the source virtual machine.</li>
            		<li>esx_snapshotname - Name of snapshot to revert to.</li>
            		<li>sdk_installation_path - Absolute path to the SDK installation lib. Default value is 'C:\Program Files\VMware\VMware vSphere CLI\Perl\lib'.</li>
		</ul>
		</p>
		
		<p class="help">
		The following fields are available for Snapshot:
                <ul>
                    	<li>connection_config - The name of the configuration that holds connection information for the ESX server (created on the Configure page).</li>
                    	<li>esx_vmname - Name of the virtual machine whose snapshot is to be created.</li>
                    	<li>esx_snapshotname - Name of the snapshot to be created.</li>
                    	<li>sdk_installation_path - Absolute path to the SDK installation lib. Default value is 'C:\Program Files\VMware\VMware vSphere CLI\Perl\lib'.</li>
                </ul>
                </p>
	
	<h2 class="help">Additional Information</h2>
		<ul>
			<li><a href="http://www.vmware.com/products/vsphere/esxi-and-esx/index.html">VMWare ESX home page</a></li>
            		<li><a href="http://communities.vmware.com/community/developer/forums/vsphere_sdk_perl">vSphere SDK for Perl home page</a></li>
            		<li><a href="http://www.vmware.com/support/developer/viperltoolkit/">vSphere SDK for Perl documentation page</a></li>            
		</ul>
        
    <h2 class="help">Release Notes</h2>
        <h3 class="help">EC-ESX-1.1.0.0</h3>
        <p class="help">
        Added the Snapshot subprodecure.
        </p>              
		
        
	</div>  </componentContainer>
</helpDefinition>
